Guide to the School of Visual and Performing Arts Collection RG 6.1.2
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Miscellaneous Original Art
  - Giacometti, Alberto; Nude, undated; 14.75 x 10.75; Charcoal (Item 50)
    Barcode: 7803W03620 | Filename: DSCF0306
  - Espinosa, J.; Captured Atom, undated; 47.25 x 27.5; oil on masonite (Item 32)
    Filename: DSCF0281
  - Timmins, Jim: Jet Stream, undated; Oil painting, 48 x 60", framed. (Item 125)
  - Timmins, Jim; Fish Weir, undated; Oil painting, 48 x 60", unframed (Item 126)
- Allen Hermes
  Allen Hermes (1913 – 2004) English born artist and sculpture, Hermes came to the United States at 16, attended school in Buffalo where he won a national poster which entitled him to a four-year scholarship at Syracuse University. He graduated with honors with a degree in fine arts and the Hazard Fellowship, which afforded him a year to study art and architecture in Germany. In 1942 Hermes married Helen Davis, daughter of Dwight Davis who served as Secretary of War in the Coolidge administration and founded the Davis Cup tennis tournament. Hermes served in World War II and after the war, settled in Redding, Connecticut. Hermes' paintings are described as being "closest to Baroque."
  Mrs. Hermes earned a master's in psychology from Western Connecticut State University later in life.
  - Hermes, Allen; Ken Bonner, undated; 30 x 38; oil on canvas (Item 26)
    Filename: DSCF0271
  - Hermes, Allen; Octopus & Uncle Sam, undated; 31 x 39; oil on canvas (Item 27)
    Filename: DSCF0272
  - Hermes, Allen; Pieta, undated; 30 x 47.75; oil on canvas (Item 28)
    Filename: DSCF0273
  - Hermes, Allen; Toreador meets Picasso, undated; 48 x 72; oil on canvas (Item 34)
    Filename: DSCF0282
  - Hermes, Allen; Dying Bull, undated; 54 x 78; oil on canvas (Item 35)
    Filename: DSCF0283
  - Hermes; Frames of Reference, undated; 54 x 78; oil on canvas (Item 36)
    Filename: DSCF0284
  - Hermes, Allen; Woman Nude, undated; 25.5 x 31.75; Drawing; Charcoal (Item 39)
    Filename: DSCF0339
  - Hermes, Allen; Portrait of a Man, undated; 9 x 10; Charcoal (Item 57)
    Filename: DSCF0342
- Robert Alberetti
  Robert Alberetti (WCSU Emeritus) began his teaching career in 1963 at WCSU and retired as a full-time professor in 2003. During that time, he spent six years as chairperson of the WCSU art department. He continues teaching occasional multidisciplinary, collage, and MFA courses. He received a BFA from Massachusetts College of Art and Design, a MA from Rhode Island School of Design and an MFA in Painting and Drawing from Arizona State University. In addition to his own art, Alberetti teaches workshops at the Caifiordi Art School in Pietralunga, Italy and the Washington Art Association, Washington, CT. He has exhibited in museums and galleries nationally and internationally. Alberetti works in oil, collage, mixed media, watercolor and encaustic.
  - 3 Alberetti paintings, 1970-2008 (Item 110-112)
    3 paintings. 72 x 42", unframed, oil on canvas; 42 x 42", framed, mixed media on canvas, entitled:"Piazza", 52 x 44", framed, oil on canvas
- Art Department Print Collection
  Scope and Contents
  During the late 1960s and early 1970s the nascent Art Department began creating a permanent collection of prints and original art for the University. WestConn hosted at least one exhibit per semester of items created by students and faculty. As items could not be purchased, pieces were according to Bob Alberetti traded for with galleries and dealers. One important gallery in this process was the Ferdinand Roten Gallery. Other pieces were acquired via a Connecticut Office of the Arts grant for purchasing items created by Connecticut artists.
  - Unknown; Big Daddy, undated; 42.5 x 32; woodcut (Item 1)
    Barcode: 7803W03613 | Filename: DSCF0214
  - Bugnon, Roland; Skurrile Landschaft, undated; 37.25 x 28.5; lithgograph (Item 3)
    Barcode: 7803W03612 | Filename: DSCF0218
  - Hermanseder, John B.; Structure, undated; 23 x 23; serigraph (Item 4)
    Barcode: 7803W03683 | Filename: DSCF0220
  - Ossi; Aquarius, undated; 27 x 20.5; etching (Item 5)
    Barcode: 7803W03664 | Filename: DSCF0221
  - Dory, George; Evening, undated; 24 x 20; color etching (Item 6)
    Barcode: 7803W03678 | Filename: DSCF0224
  - Zhouf, Georges; Reflection, undated; 27 x 21.5; lithograph (Item 7)
    Barcode: 7803W03666 | Filename: DSCF0225
  - Appel, Rosalie; Medievel Dance, undated; 26 x 205; etching (Item 8)
    Barcode: 7803W03682 | Filename: DSCF0226
  - McCray, Marilyn; Soldier 1, undated; 28.5 x 21.5; lithograph (Item 9)
    Barcode: 7803W03669 | Filename: DSCF0230
  - Sugay, Kreskin; Rising Sun, undated; 27.5 x 20; lithograph (Item 11)
    Barcode: 7803W03674 | Filename: DSCF0235
  - Tester, Kim; Settle in by Dawn, undated; 32.5 x 24; lithograph (Item 12)
    Barcode: 7803W03668 | Filename: DSCF0238
  - Mattia, Frank D.; Reclining Nude, undated; 11.25 x 13; woodcut (Box OS 1, Item 13)
    Barcode: 7803W03670 | Filename: DSCF0239
  - Motherwell, Robert; Black poster from Uconn exhibit, undated; 20 x 30; print (Box OS 1, Item 14)
    Barcode: 7803W03633 | Filename: DSCF0242
  - Dine, Jim; Tree Lamp, undated; 17 x 12; print (Box OS 1, Item 15)
    Barcode: 7803W03624 | Filename: DSCF0245
  - Fink, Herbert; Classical Kate, undated; 6 x 8.75; etching (Box OS 1, Item 16)
    Barcode: 7803W05835 | Filename: DSCF0246
  - Milam, Bucky; Landscape, undated; 25.5 x 16.5; photo reproduction print (Box OS 1, Item 17)
    Barcode: 7803W03680 | Filename: DSCF0251
  - Wolff, Roland; Meatgrinder, undated; 13.75 x 10.5; woodcut (Box OS 1, Item 18)
    Barcode: 7803W03679 | Filename: DSCF0254
  - Loffredo, Silvio; Harbor, undated; 21 x 17.5; lithograph (Box OS 1, Item 20)
    Barcode: 7803W03667 | Filename: DSCF0259
  - Allan, Terry; Prison, undated; 10 x 9; etching (Box OS 1, Item 21)
    Barcode: 7803W03642 | Filename: DSCF0264
  - Rajon, Paul-Adolphe; Self-portrait, undated; 15.5 x 14; etching (Box OS 1, Item 22)
    Barcode: 7803W03637 | Filename: DSCF0263
  - Baskin, Leonard; Life on Mars, undated; 13.75 x 12.75; wood engraving (Box OS 1, Item 23)
    Barcode: 7803W03623 | Filename: DSCF0267
  - Natkin, Robert; I Am A Golden Man, undated; 30.5 x 40; Serigraph (Item 24)
    Barcode: 7803W03671 | Filename: DSCF0268
  - Weisbuch, Claude; Sire La Ville Est Prise, undated; 37.25 x 28.75; lithgograph (Item 25)
    Barcode: 7803w03611 | Filename: DSCF0351
  - Cloutier, Albert; Sugar Time, Quebec, undated; 39 x 29.25; Print Color (Item 31)
    Filename: DSCF0277
  - Natkin, Robert; Intimate Lighting, undated; 24 x 25.75; Serigraph (reproduction) (Item 37)
    Barcode: 7803W03677 | Filename: DSCF0287
  - Rush, Andrew; Market Place Scene Hommage To Petrarch, undated; 32.5 x 27.25; Etching (Item 38)
    Barcode: 7803W03687 | Filename: DSCF0289
  - Lam, Fernando; Narcissus, undated; 22 x 28.50; Etching (Item 40)
    Barcode: 7803W03672 | Filename: DSCF0340
  - Tarag, Leticia; Un Angel, undated; 28.5 x 22.5; Etching (Item 42)
    Barcode: 7803W03684 | Filename: DSCF0294
  - Lindsey, Brian; Creation, undated; 26.75 x 23.5; Silk Screen (Item 43)
    Barcode: 7803W03673 | Filename: DSCF0295
  - Vespignani, Renzo; Fresh Fish, undated; 26.25 x 20.75; Color drawing (Item 44)
    Barcode: 7803W03675 | Filename: DSCF0296
  - Pozzatto, Rudy; Porsenna of Camars, undated; 24.75 x 20.25; Etching (Item 45)
    Barcode: 7803W03676 | Filename: DSCF0297
  - Cingier, Gustave; Tropiques, undated; 31 x 25; Etching (Item 46)
    Barcode: 7803W03614 | Filename: DSCF0298
  - Wunderlich, Paul; Song of Songs, undated; 22 x 29.5; lithograph (Item 47)
    Barcode: 7803W03618 | Filename: DSCF0300
  - Gongora, Leonel; Visio, undated; 17 x 11.75; woodcut (Item 48)
    Barcode: 7803W03665 | Filename: DSCF0304
  - Timmins, Jim; Aleutian Church, undated; 10 x 14; lithograph of color woodcut (Item 49)
    Barcode: 7803W03660 | Filename: DSCF0352
  - Enri, Hans; History of a Soldier, undated; 7 x 11; etching (Item 51)
    Barcode: 7803W03645 | Filename: DSCF0307
  - Bauer, Marius; Urbans: Engraving of Turkish Bazaar, undated; 8 x 8.5; etching (Item 52)
    Barcode: 7803W03657 | Filename: DSCF0341
  - Saucy, Claude; Eclipse I, undated; 9.25 x 6.5; etching (Item 53)
    Barcode: 7803W03640 | Filename: DSCF0348
  - Wolff, Roland; Homage to Oskar Kokshka, undated; 12 x 17; wood cut (Item 54)
    Barcode: 7803W03638 | Filename: DSCF0310
  - Saucy, Claude; Eclipse II, undated; 9.25 x 6.5; etching (Item 55)
    Barcode: 7803W03609 | Filename: DSCF0350
  - Saucy, Claude; Eclipse III, undated; 9.25 x 6.5; etching (Item 56)
    Barcode: 7803W03654 | Filename: DSCF0346
  - Manheimer, Hedy; The Masked Visitor, undated; 12.5 x 12; etching (Item 58)
    Barcode: 7803W03605 | Filename: DSCF0343
  - Loughlin, Jack; The Fly, undated; 23.25 x 18.25; print (Item 59)
    Barcode: 7803W03607 | Filename: DSCF0344
  - Wolff, Roland; Eggsorters, undated; 10.5x13.75; woodcut (Item 60)
    Barcode: 7803W03653 | Filename: DSCF0345
  - Kerkovius, Ruth; 16th Century Italian dwelling, undated; 9.25 x 5.5; etching (Item 61)
    Barcode: 7803W03631 | Filename: DSCF0319
  - Mauve, Anton; Horse and Rider, undated; 6 x 4; etching (Item 62)
    Barcode: 7803W03635 | Filename: DSCF0320
  - Baskin, Leonard; Sage, undated; 5.25 x 6; woodcut (Item 63)
    Barcode: 7803W03622 | Filename: DSCF0321
  - Langer, Raymond; #2/10 -Untitled, undated; 8 x 8; serigraph (Item 64)
    Barcode: 7803W03644 | Filename: DSCF0322
  - Unknown; Portrait of a Man, undated; 13.25 x 15; copper engraving (Item 65)
    Barcode: 7803039094 | Filename: DSCF0323
  - Abeles, Sugmund; Curled Up, undated; 6.5 x 8; drypoint (Item 66)
    Barcode: 7803W03636 | Filename: DSCF0324
  - DeMattia, F.; Nude, undated; 11.25 x 13; lithograph (Item 67)
    Barcode: 7803W03658 | Filename: DSCF0325
  - Hebram; landscape, undated; 12.75 x 10.5; colored etching (Item 68)
    Barcode: 7803W03625 | Filename: DSCF0326
  - Bernard, Emile; Odyssee, undated; 2.75 x 4; woodblock (Item 69)
    Barcode: 7803W03634 | Filename: DSCF0327
  - Anonymous; Landscape, undated; 5 x 4; etching (Item 70)
    Barcode: 7803W03629 | Filename: DSCF0328
  - Hiratsuka, Yuji; Sparkling Container I, undated; 6.5 x 5; color etching (Item 71)
    Barcode: 7803W03639 | Filename: DSCF0329
  - Hiratsuka, Yuji; Sparkling Container II, undated; 6 x 5; color etching (Item 72)
    Barcode: 7803W03603 | Filename: DSCF0330
  - Goerg, Edouard; Dante Inferno, undated; 9.25 x 7; etching (Item 73)
    Barcode: 7803W03619 | Filename: DSCF0331
  - Kaczmarek, Frank; Buoys, undated; 4x4.75; etching (Item 74)
    Barcode: 7803W03662 | Filename: DSCF0332
  - Pearson, Ralph M.; Toilers of the City, undated; 7x14; Intaglio (Item 75)
    Barcode: 7803W03606 | Filename: DSCF0333
  - Lukac, Jenni; The Twins, undated; 8x11.5; photo/oil/silver print (Item 76)
    Barcode: 7803W03632 | Filename: DSCF0334
  - Tajima, Hiroyuki; Sand Hill B, undated; 10.5 x 13.5; woodcut (Item 77)
    Barcode: 7803W03643 | Filename: DSCF0335
  - Vertes, Marcel; Old Man Two Women, undated; 9.5 x 13; lithograph (Item 78)
    Barcode: 7803W03652 | Filename: DSCF0336
  - Unknown; Drawing of De Omval by Rembrandt, undated; 7 x 8.25; etcing (Item 79)
    Barcode: 7803W03630 | Filename: DSCF0337
  - Kappel, Philip; Connecticut Idyll?, undated; 10x12.25; etching (Item 80)
    Barcode: 7803W03627 | Filename: DSCF0338
    This item was purchased via a grant from the CT Office of the Arts.
  - Chagall, Marc; Devil's Collecting Soul Artist, undated; 12x10; lithograph (Item 81)
    Barcode: 7803W03621 | Filename: DSCF0339
  - Boelke, Walter; The City, undated; 11x10.5; etching (Item 82)
    Barcode: 7803W03659 | Filename: DSCF0340
  - Whistler, J.M.; Batersea, undated; 9x12.25; etching (Item 83)
    Barcode: 7803W03641 | Filename: DSCF0341
  - Rosenhouse, Daniela; Nocturne, undated; 15.5 x 18.25; collage (Item 84)
    Barcode: 7803W03601 | Filename: DSCF0342
  - Unknown; Japanese, undated; 14.75 x 20.25; Woodblock (Item 85)
    Barcode: 7803W05836 | Filename: DSCF0343
  - Kull[pathin], Donald M.; [European Street Scene], undated; 9x7; etching (Item 86)
    Barcode: 7803W03656 | Filename: DSCF0344
  - Timmins, Jim; Yukon Fisherman, undated; 10.5x4.5; lithograph of serigraph (Item 87)
    Barcode: 7803W03661 | Filename: DSCF0345
  - Chikanobu, Yoshu; Japanese Scene, undated; 13x8.75; color woodcut (Item 88)
    Barcode: 7803W03615 | Filename: DSCF0346
  - Janak, Alois; Hermes Schuh, undated; 9x10.5; color etching (Item 89)
    Barcode: 7803W03604 | Filename: DSCF0347
  - Tajima, Hiroyuki; "Put into Print B", undated; 14x10.5; woodcut (Item 90)
    Barcode: 7803W03655 | Filename: DSCF0348
  - Loughlin, Jack; [Spider and Women], undated; 23.25x18.25; print (Item 91)
    Barcode: 7803W03607 | Filename: DSCF0349
  - Roualt, Georges; Cirque de Letoile, undated; 13x9; engraving (Item 92)
    Barcode: 7803W03608 | Filename: DSCF0350